# Filipe Constantinov Menezes

Ireland



fcmenezes87@gmail.com



+353838223915



linkedin.com/in/fcmenezes

# **Summary**

I'm software engineer with 19+ years of experience on our industry. I've worked with web technologies, desktop apps, microcontrollers and so on.

And I'm currently working on an awesome control plane called Atlas (check it out https://www.mongodb.com/ atlas).

# **Experience**



# Senior Software Engineer

## MongoDB

Jan 2021 - Present (1 year 2 months +)

- Work on projects for the Atlas Control Plane for deploying MongoDB nodes (replica sets and shards)
- Working in a Kanban environment having shared responsibilities, help to tweak team processes
- Leading projects for our infrastructure solution, one example is the project to rate limit our apis, which includes discovery of alternative solutions, running POCs, documenting scope and driving the timeline.
- Coding on a daily basis in Java, Go, Python and Javascript.

Skills: Java, Go, Python, MongoDB and React.JS

# Technical Lead

#### Zendesk

Dec 2016 - Dec 2020 (4 years 1 month)

- Telecom focused project with more than 100 thousand phone calls and 20 million http requests a day, using VoIP provider Twilio
- Leading team to deliver awesome projects and onboarding new team, running retrospectives, daily stand-ups, story writing, grooming, planning, and so on.
- Scoping and phasing projects together with Product Managers
- Defining and leading reliability projects, focused on improving stability and fault tolerance
- Focused on development environment and internal Docker tools maintenance
- Used AWS environment to maintain the infrastructure

Skills: Agile, Leadership, Mentorship, Documentation, Ruby on Rails, Go, MySQL, React.JS, Ember.JS, Twilio APIs, Docker and Datadog



## Full Stack Engineer

Maya. Ninja LLC

Jun 2014 - Oct 2016 (2 years 5 months)

- Worked on a startup environment with daily stand ups
- Created from the ground up several projects

- Idyllic: identity proofing industry focused app
- Vidyāt: library based app, mp3 and image manipulations through imagemagick
- Neuron Ninja: psychology industry focused app
- Used AWS environment to maintain the infrastructure

Skills: Javascript, Node.JS, MongoDB, Cordova (PhoneGap), Ionic Framework, Angular.JS, Bootstrap, PHP

# Senior Software Engineer

Vayon Insurance Solutions

Dec 2010 - Jan 2016 (5 years 2 months)

- Worked on on.iBusiness platform for the insurance industry
- Made a NPAPI browser plugin using C++ and later replaced by Java Applet with JNI, allowing brokers to use PINPADs to make payments through web app
- Worked with POS systems and development for microcontrollers in C
- Was in charge of architecture review during PCI-DSS certification
- Used AWS environment to maintain the infrastructure

Skills: Node.js, JavaScript, Redis, C#, MS SQL Server, C, C++, Java, JNI, Applet

## **Education**



## FIAP

Bachelor's Degree, Information Technology 2005 - 2008

# Skills

Java • Go (Programming Language) • C++ • Python (Programming Language) • Containerization • Agile Methodologies